Animation Number 1
Mayoi Jiangshi          Part Three
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Monday, August 21st, 9:17 a.m.
（忍(しのぶ)）
８月21日 月曜日 午前９時17分
Hmm, seems like the time warp succeeded the way it should have.
ふむ… タイムワープ自体は
どうやら正常に成功したようじゃぞ
21st of August
（阿良々木(あららぎ)）ん？
Lilac Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hey, Shinobu.
おい 忍
（忍）ひゃあ！
Oh, I was wondering who it was, but it's just you.
おお 誰かと思ったら お前様か
（阿良々木）
ほかに誰がいるんだよ？
Like there's anyone else? Everyone is gone!
Like smoke or fog
Animation Number 54
誰も いなくなってるよ
Should we check other houses just in case?
（忍）
お前様 一応
ほかの家も調べてみんか？
Whether it's just the Araragi house like this or the whole city...
阿良々木家だけが こうなのか
それとも町全体が
こうなっておるのか
I don't think it's worth it to check.
（阿良々木）
確認するまでもねえと思うがな
However, we need to confirm it.
（忍）
しかし 確認せねばなるまいよ
We have that responsibility.
その責任があろう
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
From there, not only did we inspect all our neighbors' houses, but all over town as well.
（阿良々木）
それから 僕たちは
近隣の家のみならず
Stop
Wait        Here
2    0
8-20
町の あちらこちらを
検分することにした
It took a long time. Roughly five hours.
たっぷり およそ５時間ほどかけて
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Now...
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
さてと
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
The world has been annihilated.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
世界が滅んでるぞ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Yup.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Well, that was a cute answer.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
返事が かわいいな
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Yup.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
In other words, because you...
（阿良々木）
つまり これは お前が
For no good reason
Animation Number 73
（忍）
お前様が あの迷子っ娘(こ)を
Because you...
we tried to
Animation Number 75
carelessly...
（阿良々木）不用意に
（忍）助けたために
saved that girl...
blame each other
Animation Number 78
and created a slip in time...
We pushed the blame away
Animation Number 80
（阿良々木）
タイムスリップをしたせいで
like two
Animation Number 81
...history has
（２人）
歴史が変わってしまった
...history has
changed.
pitiful
Animation Number 84
I can't...
（忍）としか
（阿良々木）ということで
There's definitely no mistake.
clowns.
Animation Number 87
（阿良々木）
間違いがないよ
think of another explanation.
（忍）考えられん
（阿良々木）だな
Right.
No good! The whole world? It's on such a scale I simply can't grasp the reality of it.
ダメだ！　世界って…
スケールが大きすぎて
全然 現実感が湧いてこない
衝撃的すぎて
パニックにもなれない
It's so shocking I can't even panic.
Karen and Tsukihi are missing.
火憐(かれん)や月火(つきひ)が
行方不明になっちゃってるのに
Senjougahara, Hanekawa, Kanbaru, and Sengoku, they're nowhere to be seen.
戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)も羽川(はねかわ)も神原(かんばる)も千石(せんごく)も
見当たらないっていうのに
Yet I can't bring myself to grieve and lament. Honestly, that's pretty shocking.
嘆き悲しむことができない自分が
正直かなりショックだぜ
But I can't just sit here and cry about it.
でも 泣きわめけねえよ
ハア さすがに これは…
As expected, this is...
But what does this mean? So, after Hachikuji's close call, and her life being extended...
しかし これは一体
どういうことだ？
つまり 八九寺(はちくじ)が あのあと
本来よりも延びた寿命の間に
...did something preposterous happen, causing the world to be destroyed?
何か とんでもないことを
しでかして
世界を滅ぼす原因を
作ったとでもいうのか？
（忍）
いや あの娘に そこまでの
器があったとは思わんが…
No, I don't think that girl was of that caliber...
Animation Number 106
This means it's likely that, on the night of June 14th...
（阿良々木）これは つまり
どうやら６月14日の夜半ごろに
夕刊が配り終えられ
...after the evening papers were delivered, but before the morning ones, something happened.
そして 朝刊が作られる前に
何かが起こって
It's like Dee-Dee pushed the big red button.
Animation Number 109
Something of some nature happened, and the world was annihilated all in one shot. Not gradually.
It's like Dee-Dee pushed the big red button.
Animation Number 109
何らかの
何かが起こって
It's like Dee-Dee pushed the big red button.
Animation Number 109
This is pretty SF.
そして 段階的にではなく
一気呵成(かせい)に 崩壊的に
世界は滅んだということを
意味していると
判断していいんじゃないかな
I think that's what we can conclude from this.
これは 何らかの怪異現象だって
考えるべきなんじゃないか？
Maybe this is some aberration-based phenomenon.
歴史の強制力や
運命の修正論とかいうのから
外れられるのは
怪異だけなんだろ？
Only aberrations can act outside the forces of history and destiny, right?
That's why we could travel through time and prevent Hachikuji from turning into an aberration.
だから お前には
時間移動ができるし
八九寺の怪異化を
防ぐことができた
I see. That's a viable story.
なるほどな　ありそうな話じゃ
My logic probably holds water.
Animation Number 116
Shinobu is thinking about something.
Animation Number 117
What's wrong, Shinobu?
（阿良々木）どうした？　忍
I was trying to think of something, but I can't remember.
（忍）
いや… 何か
思いつきそうじゃったのじゃが
いまいち ピンとこないのじゃ
My memory really fails me.
わしの記憶力は
本当にポンコツじゃのう
What? Got a hunch?
なんだよ 心当たりでもあるのか？
Just that.
Animation Number 122
About why the world's like this?
世界が こんなふうに
なっちまった理由に
She seemed like she was really troubled.
Animation Number 122
And if that's the case, about the aberration that turned the world into this mess?
もしも そうだったのならだけれど
世界を こんなふうに
しちまった怪異に
（忍）う〜ん そうなのかのう
I wonder if that's it...
For now, something came of this. We found out the date the world fell.
まあ とりあえず
収穫は あったのう
世界が滅んだ日付は 判明した
Right. But the question is what happened to the world that day and that night.
（阿良々木）そうだな
しかし 問題は その日その夜
一体 何があったのかということだ
それが分からないことには
手の打ちようがないぜ
There's no counter without knowing that.
Counter? Even in this situation, you're thinking of doing something to counter it?
（忍）手の打ちよう？
お前様 この状況に対して
何か手を打つつもりなのか？
Well, if it's like people were spirited away...
いや もしも
神隠しみたいな状況ならさ
その怪異問題を解決すれば
If we solve that aberration problem, everyone can come back to this world, right?
みんな この世界に
帰ってこられるわけだろ？
I don't really know, to be honest.
Animation Number 128
Even if we can't fill in the two-month gap, we can at least correct the world to how it was originally.
この２か月の空白を
埋めることはできなくっても
世界を元どおりに修正することは
きっとできる
Not like there's any certainty, though.
Animation Number 130
So I want to know why the world was annihilated.
だから 僕は
世界が滅んだ原因を知りたいんだ
I see.
（忍）そうか
Let's go look into the reason.
それでは
原因を調べに行くとするか
If we time slip again, to the evening of June 14th...
もう一度
過去にタイムスリップして
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
６月14日の夜に行けば
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
...what happened should become clear.
Evening Paper
Wednesday   June 14th
一体 何があったかは
はっきりするじゃろう
Animation Number 139
ん？　どうした？
What's wrong?
February, 1919
Donor
（忍）うむ
There's absolutely zero energy left.
エネルギーが
まるっきり残っておらん
（阿良々木）そっか
I see.
The cause is, let's see... Probably that.
（忍）原因は そうじゃのう
あれ… かのう
Huh? This is...
あれ？　これって…
Reminiscence
Animation Number 151
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It's not the same type of talisman. What does this mean?
違う札だぞ これ
どういうことだ？
Rather than the type, the effect is different.
（忍）
種類というより
効果が違うんじゃよ
The talisman you got from Hawaiian-shirt guy is different in the histories before and after the change.
変わる前の歴史と
変わったあとの歴史とでは
お前様が アロハ小僧から
渡された札が別なんじゃ
Animation Number 155
Different Effect
Animation Number 156
In short, not only is this about the world's fate, but various trivial details of history, like this, have also changed.
（忍）
つまり 世界の存亡のみならず
こういった ささいなところでも
いろいろと歴史が
変わっておるということじゃな
（阿良々木）ふ〜ん
Though it's not trivial for us.
（忍）
わしらにとっては
ささいなことではないがの
The talisman you attached dispersed the spiritual energy so that it didn't collect.
お前が貼ったお札は
霊的エネルギーが
まとまらないように散らす薬
The talisman that's in front of us now is one that absorbs spiritual energy.
今 わしらの目の前にあるお札は
霊的エネルギーを
吸収する札なのじゃ
The spiritual energy necessary for a time warp
Animation Number 163
（阿良々木）
きゅ… 吸収？
A-Absorbs?
has been absorbed
Animation Number 163
and we were never able to go back in time.
It's several orders of magnitude more extreme than the one you were given.
（忍）
お前様が託されたものよりも
数段 効能が
過激な札ということじゃよ
まあ 妖怪大戦争を防ぐ
という意味では
The result's the same in that you're preventing a great aberration war...
結果は同じなんじゃが…
I see...
（阿良々木）そうだな
Like a burst of anger
Animation Number 165
Well, I know this'll sound irrelevant and hypocritical...
まあ こんなこと言うのは
自分のことを棚に上げた—
筋違いだということは
分かっちゃいるけれど
...but since nobody is listening, I'm going to say something selfish.
それでも どうせ誰も
聞いてないからと思って
勝手なことを言ってしまうか
What'd you do, Oshino!
何してくれんだよ 忍野(おしの)！
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（忍）まあ 勝手じゃのう
Well, that is selfish. It didn't matter to him which talisman was used because the result was the same.
アロハ小僧にしてみれば
別に どっちの札を使おうと
同じことじゃからのう
But he's not so random he'd do something this drastic from sticky fingers or luck.
（阿良々木）
ただ まあ 手癖や指運で
こんな大事なことをするほど
適当な男でもないと思うから
きっと この歴史ならではの
So I think there was a reason to in this history. But even if we found out, it's probably already pointless.
必然的な理由が
あったんだと思うけれど
それを追及したところで
既に 意味がないだろうな
（忍）そうじゃのう
Right.
（阿良々木）
ハア 賽銭(さいせん)でも放り込んで
I'll just have to toss in some change and pray to the gods now.
神頼みでもするしかねえかな
こうなったら
Oh, wait...
あっ 待てよ
If we peel this talisman off and wait patiently, wouldn't the so-called spiritual energies start to pile up again?
この お札を剥がして
それから ずっと
気を長くして待っていれば
また この場所に
霊的エネルギーってやつが
たまっていくんじゃないのか？
（忍）お前様！
（阿良々木）うっ
You!
Absorption
Animation Number 181
（阿良々木）ううっ うわあ！
Bang
Animation Number 182
This talisman is not the type that you or I...
（忍）
この札は
お前様や わしといった—
...those who belong to the category of aberration, can touch.
怪異に属する者が
触れる種類の札ではない
I see. Then it's time to despair.
（阿良々木）そうか　では絶望だな
Despair it is.
（忍）絶望じゃのう
Animation Number 196
（阿良々木）ああっ
（忍）な… 何じゃ？　これは
Wh-What are these!
Zombies...
Rotten Corpses
Animation Number 205
（阿良々木）
ゾンビ？
Caught between life and death for all eternity
Animation Number 207
Don't you move...
（忍）動くなよ お前様
As long as we're here, they can't creep in any closer.
とりあえず ここにいれば
こやつらは これ以上
近寄っては来んようじゃ
Huh? Oh...
（阿良々木）え？　ああ…
Buy why? Why can't they come any closer?
どうしてだ？
しかし どうして こいつら
これ以上 近づいて来ないんだ？
Probably the talisman. This is about the limit of how close they can get to it.
この札のせいじゃろうな
この連中は近づけて
ここまでなのじゃろう
これ以上は危険じゃと
分かっておるのじゃ
They probably know coming closer is dangerous.
They know?
（阿良々木）分かっている？
For now, it seems we're safer to get away from here while this talisman is still effective.
とりあえず 霊験あらたかな
お札の効果があるうちに
ここからは離れたほうが
よさそうじゃ
Get away? Aren't we safe as long as we stay here?
（阿良々木）え？　離れる？
ここにいる限り
安全じゃあないのか？
As you can see, the numbers are increasing. I honestly can't grasp the full situation.
（忍）お前様も 見てのとおり
どんどん人数が
増えてきておるからのう
はっきり言って状況が読めん
And well, because they're aberrations, I don't think they're our enemies.
また なんじゃ
怪異である以上 わしや
それに お前様の
敵ではないとも思うが
And if they're the town residents turned into zombies, you can't just mow them down!
この町の住人の死体で作られた
ゾンビかもしれんと思うと
うかつに
蹴散らすわけにもいかんじゃろう
（阿良々木）そうだな
You're right.
So for now, we're going to make our escape!
（忍）
じゃから とりあえず逃げるぞ
お前様！
（阿良々木）うわあ！
For now, we've managed to escape!
とりあえず
これで脱出には成功したのう
（阿良々木）ああ
Yeah, but what in the world were they?
しかし 一体 何だったんだ？
あいつらは
I don't know... But wait, they probably weren't zombies, but rather...
（忍）分からん
いや しかし あれは
ゾンビというよりは むしろ…
（忍）あっ
（阿良々木）ああ！
（阿良々木）ああ！　なんてこった
What the hell...
I can't possibly have an excuse for this. A mishap I can't atone for...
これは さすがに
言い訳のしようもなく
償いようのない過ちだぜ
I didn't think because I slipped through time and tried to change the past, I'd turn all humanity into zombies...
僕がタイムスリップして
過去を変えようとしたばかりに
まさか 全人類を
ゾンビにしてしまうだなんて…
No, this is not something you need to worry over.
（忍）いや お前様
これは お前様が
気に病むようなことではない
I'm to blame.
悪いのは わしじゃ
It's all my fault.
全ては わしのせいじゃ
What do you mean? I'm happy you care for me, but Shinobu, I was the one...
（阿良々木）どういうことだよ？
気持ちは うれしいが…
だけど 忍
だって 僕は…
No, I'm not saying this to cover for you.
（忍）
いや
かばって言っておるのではなく
It is an undeniable fact. It is the hard truth.
ただの厳然たる事実じゃ
厳しい現実じゃ
Shinobu!
（阿良々木）忍…
（忍）いいから聞くがよい
It's okay, just listen.
First off, those aren't zombies. Those are what used to be vampires.
まず お前様
ありゃゾンビじゃなくて
吸血鬼の成れの果てじゃ
Vamp——ire
Animation Number 291
Vampires?
（阿良々木）吸… 血鬼？
I guess you could say they're just like you.
（忍）
お前様１人と同じ…
と言うべきじゃろうな
Because all of them, just like you, were humans who I turned into vampires.
なぜなら あやつらは
お前様と同じく
わしに吸血鬼化された
元人間なのじゃから
Used
Animation Number 300
to be
human
Animation Number 300
You did?
（阿良々木）お前が？
（忍）そう
Right.
In other words, in this version of history, the one that annihilated the world...
つまり この歴史において
この世界を滅ぼしたのは
...is me.
わしなのじゃ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 196
We maintained an altitude of 300 m and waited for sunrise.
（阿良々木）
そのまま高度300メートルを保って
僕たちは夜明けを待った
And dawn...
そして 夜明け
Right around when the sun rose from the eastern sky, the swarm of zombies simply disappeared from the land.
太陽が東の空から
昇ってきたところで
あっさりと地上から
ゾンビの群れは姿を消した
22nd of August
So what do you mean that it's your fault, Shinobu? Tell me.
（阿良々木）
で お前のせいってのは
どういう意味なんだよ？　忍
教えてくれ
My fault.
（忍）わしのせい
Or rather, it's the fault of who I am in this version of history.
正確には この歴史における
わしのせいじゃ
（阿良々木）
ん？　この歴史っていうのは
By "this version of history," you're talking about the Oshino Shinobu in this history that we changed, right?
Main Street
つまり 変わってしまった
僕たちが変えてしまった
この歴史における
忍野忍という意味だよな？
Right. Myself in this world... the me that isn't myself...
（忍）
そう この世界のわしが
わしならぬ わしが２か月前に
...turned all of humanity into vampires two months ago. That's what I mean.
いわゆる全人類を吸血鬼化した—
ということじゃ
June 14th.
（忍）６月14日
（阿良々木）ん？
I finally remembered what day that was, just moments ago.
（忍）
その日が何の日だったか
さっき ようやく思い出せたのじゃ
What day that was?
（阿良々木）
その日が何の日だったかって…
You should remember it as well. It should've been a rather memorable day.
（忍）
お前様も覚えておるはずじゃぞ
印象深い日のはずじゃ
Doesn't it ring any bells?
何かピンとこんか？
It was the day that the world was annihilated. Of course it's going to be rather memorable.
（阿良々木）
そりゃ 世界が滅んだ日なんだろ？
印象深くて当たり前だ
The night of June 14th, or even June 15th...
６月14日の夜
あるいは６月15日って…
No, not that! I mean the original evening of June 14th. What happened that night in the original history.
（忍）
違う 違う
そうではなく 本来の…
元の歴史における
６月14日の夜じゃ
June 14th...
（阿良々木）６月14日ねえ
14th... 14th...
14日…
Let's see, it was Wednesday, so the 15th was a Thursday...
えっと 水曜日だから
15日は木曜日で…
Guess it's not ringing a bell.
（忍）ピンとこんようじゃの
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Maybe you'll get it if I say that June 15th was the day before what you called the school festival.
６月15日が文化祭とやらの
前日であると言えば
お前様にも分かるかのう
（阿良々木）ああ
Reminiscence
Animation Number 404
Looks like you realized what it was.
（忍）
気付いたようじゃのう
Yeah...
You really are the worst guy. It was the day of your first date with your girlfriend.
Parking
（忍）
最低の男じゃのう
恋人との初デートの日付も
It was the day that the ex-class Prez, who you keep saying is the one saved your life, faced a dire crisis.
普段から あれだけ恩人恩人
言っておる 元委員長の身に
重大事件があった日付も
It was the day I ran away from home and that Hawaiian-shirt guy left town.
わしの家出も
アロハ小僧が去っていった日付も
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
And you had completely forgotten all of that!
全部まとめて忘れておったとは
Animation Number 418
But what does all that matter? I still don't get it.
（阿良々木）
だけど だから どういうことなのか
って言われても
やっぱり分からないぞ
It's true all sorts of things happened, but the world wasn't annihilated or anything.
いろいろあったのは確かだけれど
だからといって 世界が滅んだりは
しなかったじゃないか
強いて言うなら
If anything, it'd be Black Hanekawa running rampant, which would be tied to an aberration phenomenon...
ブラック羽川の跳梁(ちょうりょう)が
怪異現象には つながるけれど…
No, there's an association with Black Hanekawa as part of the phenomenon...
（忍）
いや ブラック羽川も
現象としては無関係ではないが
...but what's important is my having run away from home.
重要なのは
わしの家出のほうじゃ
You having run away from home? But that was something solved rather uneventfully...
（阿良々木）お前の家出？
でも あれこそ
何事もなく解決して…
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
No, that's not true.
（阿良々木）
いや 違う
It was solved rather uneventfully only in the history that we know, that we experienced.
何事もなく解決したのは
あくまでも僕たちの知る
僕たちの経験した歴史であって
So, in this history, some event resulted from it?
つまり この歴史では
何事かがあったのか
Is she saying it wasn't resolved?
解決しなかったとでもいうのか
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I ended up never talking to you about the details of my having run away from home...
（忍）
結局 あの家出の詳細について
わしは お前様に
何も語っておらんし
...and you chose not to ask me.
お前様も あえて
わしに聞きはせんかった
I was grateful for your understanding. Therefore, I'm not going to go into the details now.
その気遣いは ありがたいと思うし
じゃから ここでも詳しい話を
するつもりはないのじゃが
But I will disclose one fact that I can't keep hiding anymore.
しかし １つだけ ここで
隠しきれん事実を開示するとしよう
Sure. Go ahead.
（阿良々木）
おう もったいぶるなよ
I was planning on annihilating the world if you hadn't found me that day.
（忍）
あの日 わしは お前様が
わしを見つけてくれんかったら
世界を滅ぼすつもりでいた
That event was that important? W-Why?
（阿良々木）
あれって
そんな大ごとだったのか？
な… なんで？
Merely being desperate, or rather, taking out my aggression on others.
（忍）
自暴自棄というか
八つ当たりじゃのう
どちらかと言えば
So, in this world—this is rather confusing, but—
（阿良々木）
つまり この世界の
えっと… ややこしいけれど
In this version of history, Araragi Koyomi was unable to find you on June 14th?
この歴史の阿良々木暦(こよみ)は
あの６月14日に
お前を見つけることが
できなかったってことになるのか？
That's probably what happened.
（忍）
そういうことに なるのじゃろうな
Reminiscence
Animation Number 449
Think about it.
考えてもみよ
The one that realized I had run away from home in the first place was that lost girl.
そもそも あの日
わしの家出に最初に気付いたのは
あの迷子っ娘じゃったろう？
No, it's not just limited to that day.
（阿良々木）
いや その日に限った
話ではないのだ
Hachikuji. If Hachikuji doesn't exist as an aberration...
八九寺
怪異としての八九寺がいなくなれば
６月14日どころか
...not only would the events of June 14th not happen, but I never would've met Hachikuji that Mother's Day.
5    6    7    8    9   10    11      12     13
May
そもそも あの母の日に
僕が 八九寺に出会うことはない
So, the Araragi Koyomi of this world is an Araragi Koyomi that has never met Hachikuji Mayoi.
つまり この世界の阿良々木暦は
Namashiro Residential Complex
八九寺真宵(まよい)と出会っていない
阿良々木暦なのだ
（阿良々木）あ… そっか
I see. If that's the case, Black Hanekawa probably killed me that night.
だとすると 僕は あのときに
多分 ブラック羽川に
殺されたんだな
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Shinobu, this is another question that if you don't want to, you don't have to answer, so listen with a light heart.
忍 これも答えたくなかったら
答えなくてもいい質問なんで
相当に軽い気持ちで
聞いてもらっていいんだけれど
Honestly, I didn't think about this question, nor did I ever want to think about it...
つうか 僕は正直—
考えたことも
考えたくもなかった質問なんだが
But how does it work?
どうなんだ？
You and I have tied ourselves to each other, all the way from spring break up to now.
（阿良々木）
僕とお前は こうやって
互いが互いを縛ってる状態が
春休みから
ずっと続いているけれど
In this situation, if you or I...
この状態で僕なのか お前なのか
If one of us dies from an unfortunate accident, what happens to the other?
どちらか一方が
不慮の事故で命を落とした場合
Because we tied ourselves together, will one death cause the other to die?
もう一方は
果たして どうなるんだ？
縛り合ってる以上 一緒に
道連れで死ぬことになるのか？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Or...
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
それとも…
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
The answer is "Or."
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（忍）
〝それとも〞の
ほうじゃな
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
That airhead of a cat girl probably never understood this...
あの おつむの足らん猫娘は
絶対に
分かっておらんかったじゃろうが
...but at the least, the Hawaiian-shirt guy probably knew.
まあ あのアロハ小僧は
分かっておったはずじゃな
You were told before, right?
お前様も言われたことがあったろう
You can go back to being a human whenever you want. All you need to do is abandon me.
わしを見捨てれば
いつでも人間に戻ることができると
Animation Number 478
In other words, if we flip that thought and I were to die...
（阿良々木）
つまり それは 裏を返せば
僕が殺されれば
...you'd regain your powers and become the most powerful, legendary vampire.
お前は元の力を取り戻し
最強にして伝説の吸血鬼に…
You could revert back into a vampire of blood and iron, zeal, and cold calculation.
A vampire of
Animation Number 481
鉄血にして 熱血にして
冷血の吸血鬼に
blood and iron,
Animation Number 481
zeal,
and cold calculation.
Animation Number 481
返り咲くことができるわけだ
And I took the idea of annihilating the world seriously.
（忍）
そして わしは
本気で世界を滅ぼしたのじゃろう
Specifically, I turned everyone in this town...
具体的には この町じゅうの人間を
Everyone in Japan...
日本中の人間を
Everyone in the world...
世界中の人間を
Into vampires.
吸血鬼化したのじゃろう
Since the Industrial Revolution, the world population has
World Population
2050 9.3bn
2011 7bn
1998 6bn
1987 5bn
1950 2.5bn
Beginning of
Industr. Revolution
Bubonic Plague
Rise of Ancient
Empires
Emergence of
Commerce and
Agriculture
First Homo Sapiens
3000 BC          AD 500
1000           1500           2000
0.5
Population in Bn
You turned all humans into vampires, huh?
（阿良々木）
人間を全て 吸血鬼化…
Well, in reality, I probably only directly sucked blood from the first few people.
（忍）
まあ 現実には
わしが直接 血を吸ったのは
最初の数人
といったところじゃろうがな
Those select few, like me, would become vampires that want to destroy the world...
その数人は わし同様に
世界を滅ぼそうとする吸血鬼となり
...and keep sucking the life out of everyone around them.
周囲の人間から
吸血し続けるということじゃ
Vampire
Trace the vampires born that way back to their roots and you would find my servants.
そうやって生まれた吸血鬼もまた
遡れば わしの眷族(けんぞく)
Vampire
Vampires that wanted to destroy the world just like I did.
同じように
世界を滅ぼそうとする吸血鬼じゃ
And so, like a pyramid scheme, the numbers increase in a geometric progression...
そうやって ネズミ算的に
等比数列的に増殖していき
...and before you know it, it destroyed the world. Or rather, what you call humanity.
あっという間に 世界を…
というより 人という種を
滅ぼしたのじゃろう
But, according to that theory, I'm dead, but you're not, right?
（阿良々木）
でも その話だと
僕は死んでるけれど
お前は死んでないだろ？
Where and what are you doing in this history?
この歴史のお前は 今
どこで何をしているんだ？
What about you, after you destroyed this world? Well...
世界を滅ぼしてしまったあとの
お前は えっと…
You're here, so...
お前が ここにいるんだから…
I believe that I'm already dead in this version of history.
恐らく この歴史の わしは
既に死んでおる
ああっ 死んで…
Dead?
It's obvious. There's only one person that can kill me at full power...
（忍）言うまでもない
全盛期のわしを殺せる者など
１人しかおらん
And that is none other than myself.
ほかならぬ わしじゃ
In other words, suicide.
つまり 自殺じゃな
（阿良々木）ああ…
And because I died, all the vampire servants turned into zombies.
（忍）
そして わしが
死んでしまったがゆえに
眷族の吸血鬼が
全員ゾンビ化したというわけじゃよ
In order to return from vampire to human, there was the thought of killing you with my own hands.
（阿良々木）
吸血鬼から 人間に戻るためには
自分の手で お前を殺すって
方法があるけれど
But if you're already dead, there's no way to get them all back to normal.
本人である
お前が死んじまってるんじゃ
戻りようもないしな
We have to just let the vampiric blood run rampant.
吸血鬼の血が暴走するのに
任せるしかないわけか
I'm sorry.
（忍）ごめんなさい
（阿良々木）え？
I didn't mean to do this.
（忍）
こんなことを
するつもりではなかった
I just wanted you to find me.
わしは ただ お前様に
見つけてほしいだけじゃった
But with that pouting, child-like reason, I destroyed the entire world that you held dear.
それなのに あんな
子供が すねたみたいな理由で
お前様の大切な世界を
滅ぼしてしまうだなんて…
Stop it.
やめろ
Don't apologize.
謝るな
Don't blame yourself.
自分を責めるな
It's true that the version of you in this history destroyed history itself, but that's not you.
確かに この歴史のお前が
この歴史を
滅ぼしたのかもしれないけれど
それは お前とは違う
お前じゃないか
Th-That's right, but it's still me.
（忍）
そ… それは そうじゃが
わしには違いがない
In any case, Shinobu, you don't have to apologize anymore; you didn't do anything wrong.
（阿良々木）
とにかく 忍
もう謝らなくていいよ
お前は何も悪くない
At least the "you" who is standing in front of me right now.
少なくとも 今 僕の前にいるお前は
From here on, just the two of us, in this ruined world...
（阿良々木）
これから先 たった２人で
この滅んだ世界で
Don't block
entrances
and line up
Don't block
entrances
and line up
Take care
when train
arrives
誰もいない恐ろしい世界で
In this horrible world where nobody else exists and tons of zombies run around...
そして 大量のゾンビが闊歩(かっぽ)する
おぞましい世界で
...we have to keep living.
僕たちは
生きていかなくちゃいけないんだ
We need to help each other now more than ever.
今まで以上に 助け合っていこうぜ
You...
（忍）
お前様…
You didn't do anything wrong, Shinobu.
（阿良々木）
忍は 何も悪くない
Animation Number 557
Wholesale
（阿良々木）ん…
What's wrong?
（忍）どうした？　お前様
（阿良々木）いや えっと…
Well, uh...
I want to try something out.
１つ 試してみたいことができた
What's the point of launching those?
（忍）
そんな物を打ち上げて
どうするのじゃ？
Though, it could be good to decorate the end of summer.
まあ 日本の夏の終わりを飾るには
いい趣向かもしれぬが…
True, it's pretty stylish to enjoy fireworks all alone with you.
（阿良々木）
いや そりゃあ お前と２人きりで
花火を楽しむってのも
スゲえ おつじゃあ
あるんだけれどな
This world looks like it's been annihilated, but perhaps there's a one-in-a-million chance...
一見 滅びたと思える
この世界ではあるが
ひょっとしたら 誰か
万一だけれど 生き残ってるヤツが
いるかもしれないだろ？
...someone may still have survived.
How to put it... Like people hiding in fear of the masses of zombies that show up every night.
何て言うか…
夜になれば現れる
大量のゾンビに怯えて
隠れ住んでるヤツが…
ふむ
Animation Number 614
Three Days Later, Afternoon
So that the light of the fireworks could reach as far as possible...
（阿良々木）
せめて少しでも遠くまで
花火の光が届くように
The Big Fireworks Day
Animation Number 614
Nobody could have wished
for better weather for fireworks.
Animation Number 614
...we decided to wait for a cloudy day to launch the fireworks.
曇りの日を待ってから
花火を打ち上げようと
Three Days Later, Clouds
Animation Number 615
26th of August
僕らは決めた
Tamaya!
（阿良々木）た〜まや〜！
Kagiya!
（忍）か〜ぎや〜！
Now, let's wait for a while until it turns into night.
（阿良々木）
さて これで しばらく
夜になるまで待ってみるか
Yeah.
（阿良々木）
まあ あくまでも変な期待は
しないようにはしておこう
Well, that said, let's not have any strange expectations.
Even if there really is a chance someone survived through all this and is living in hiding...
本当に万が一 誰かが難を逃れて
生きて潜んでいたところで
...I don't think they'd be lured out here by fireworks of this sort.
こんな花火に釣られて
出て来てくれるとも思えないしな
Mankind was annihilated at the hands of vampires, so it'd be natural for them to think this a trap.
人類が吸血鬼の手で
滅ぼされてしまったんだ
ワナかと思うのが普通だろう
Besides...
それに…
Come now!
（忍）こら！
（阿良々木）ぐああ〜！
That didn't hurt so much that you should yell that loud.
（忍）
そんな大声で悲鳴を上げるほど
痛いわけがなかろう
It's not good to expect too much, but you can't do anything if you're being overly pessimistic.
過度な期待を持つのは よくないが
かといって 過度に
悲観的になっては何もできまい
If you just wait thinking it's useless, nothing will come of it.
ムダだ ムダだと思いながら
待ち続けるくらいじゃったら
It'd be better to think about how you'd communicate with a survivor who was lured out by this
おびき寄せられて
のこのこ出てきた生き残りの人間と
上手にコミュニケーションを
取る方法でも考えておけ
The person might not be a girl of junior high age.
相手は女子中学生とは限らんぞ
True.
そうだな
Animation Number 654
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Red Scene
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐）火憐だぜ！
（月火）月火だよ！
Karen here!
And Tsukihi!
I'm Tsukihi!
（月火･可憐）
２人合わせて
“ファイヤーシスターズ”！
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
Slant
Preview Quiz!
Out looking for the Ten Wonders
from the Past,
to get a taste of the Dreamy Donut.
How about some time travel?
Your mission: buy one of these.
（月火）予告編クイズ
（火憐）クイズ！
Quiz!
（月火）
私 阿良々木月火が
歌った名曲といえば
You know that famous song by Araragi Tsukihi, "Platinum Disco"?
「白金(プラチナ)ディスコ」ですが
（火憐）
人が自分で名曲って言うのを
聞くと引くなあ
Hearing you say this just make me feel like ignoring you.
（月火）
言葉として ディスコのほうから
先に覚えちゃったから
Knowing the meaning of the word "Disco",
Back to the age of the Ten Wonders...
私 ディストピアって
I had assumed "Dystopia" meant some kind of wonderful utopia.
すっごく楽しい
理想郷のことだと思ってたよ
ユートピアの上が
ディストピアなんだって思ってた
I really thought dystopia surpassed utopia!
Eh? Sold out moments ago?
And here we came just for them!
（火憐）
大胆な勘違いだな
That's quite a bold misconception.
（月火）
ちなみに ユートピアは
By the way, I also believed "Utopia" meant a city of academic excellency,
優等な都市のことだと思ってた
because I had learned the word for "Academic excellency" beforehand.
優等って言葉のほうを
先に覚えちゃったから
（火憐）
ディスコピアに 優等ピアかよ
"Discopia" in "Excellencia" then? Now, do you know what a "Shakespeare" is?
This world deserves to be destroyed...
EH!
じゃあ シェイクスピアは
何なんだよ？
What sort of question is that? Shakespeare is a playwright.
（月火）
シェイクスピアは 劇作家でしょう
火憐ちゃん 何 言ってるの？
（火憐）
ここをディストピアに
してやろうか！
This has become my dystopia!
Next time! Kabukimonogatari Episode 4!
Next Time
Mayoi Jiangshi Part 4
（火憐･月火）
次回「傾(かぶき)物語」
第４話「まよいキョンシー其ノ肆(そのよん)」
Mayoi Jiangshi, Part 4.
Oh, you know I also thought "Platinum" was a hard plastic of some sort.
You recreated them in our time?
（月火）
ちなみにプラチナを
プラスチックの
丈夫な物体かと思ってた
（火憐）
血生臭い物体だと
思ってなくてよかったぜ
Thank god you didn't mistake "Bloody beating" for something else!